<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Anirudh Sharma</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Anirudh Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/blog/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>with all the summer love- The Indian iPad!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/with-all-the-summer-love-the-indian-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/with-all-the-summer-love-the-indian-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am waiting to see what happens to the indigenous Notion Ink Adam and Apple iPad. Will it even turn out to be a war? Both are not released yet- but the coming summer isn&amp;rsquo;t far away too. Should i quote &amp;ldquo;breathless anticipation usually reserved by nubile nymphets for rakish rockers.&amp;rdquo; :-P&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Notion Ink Adam tablet with its Pixel Qi display&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adam beats iPad hands down in all hardware specs. The hardware, the software ( Yay! Android and Ubuntu combo is superawesome) but yes we know of the Apple&amp;rsquo;s marketing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOSS GN09 Coming Up Soon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:8000/blog/foss-gn09-coming-up-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:8000/blog/foss-gn09-coming-up-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve planned a FOSS event in college from 28-31st October. We&amp;rsquo;ll be talking to people about enhancing their contribution to the commnity, code, and the spirit behind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably we&amp;rsquo;ll be having &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.niyam.com/&#34;&gt;Niyam Bhushan&lt;/a&gt;. So we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking and doing an unconference on Human Computer Interaction, Multitouch, programming gestures, why a programmer should consider design while writing code etc. We&amp;rsquo;ve also planned to do a hackfest on how to build a DIY multitouch table with junk hardware etc. and writing some gestures code in AS3&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
