<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Multitouch CAD on Anirudh Sharma</title>
    <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/tags/multitouch-cad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Multitouch CAD on Anirudh Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://anirudh.me/blog/tags/multitouch-cad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Google SoC: I am in :)</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-i-am-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-i-am-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After falcon4ever and tito&amp;rsquo;s hint I was keeping my fingers crossed. Phew ! at 12:30 AM IST 22 April dot, the results for Google Summer of Code -2009 were announced. Sudhanshu broke me the news on call, I was in ! It was one of the best moments of my life- the feeling within was a mix of several emotions. The mood was upbeat, yet I had in mind the upcoming summer ahead. Being selected is just the beginning, the real groundwork starts now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed an idea for GSoC 2009</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/proposed-an-idea-for-gsoc-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/proposed-an-idea-for-gsoc-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proposed an Idea for Google Summer of Code to port Google SketchUp to Multitouch. Users would be able to do 3D modeling with simple and intuitive gestures. An Extension Module that would allow Google SketchUp to receive TUIO and hence allow manipulations via Multitouch gestures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lack of a CAD software that could be used via Multitouch has been the motivating factor behind this proposal. Eversince I used the Sketches application on iPhone &amp;ndash; which enables 2D drawing using Multitouch, I felt like doing something similar on my FTIR setup. Adding multitouch ability to an easy to use CAD/modeling software - Google SketchUp would not only make the design process intuitive but also add a lot to the usability factor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CAD Designs for the table</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-cad-designs-for-the-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-cad-designs-for-the-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEixnIXXzqxqROHY9v7sLdygjJF_2TP-7gDTGRqO3v2yzYREce55iRfm1BIgHyxHWDe6KSztvVKfCpZdSu3Uk3RKMKydaR7DhMpMBJfDBfM6Gzit4weTD1NY5iDTkSc4uFIcElH2RsH0CJG7/s1600/sparsh.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CAD design showing adjustable projector rails and shoe-strip mount&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;CAD design showing adjustable projector rails and shoe-strip mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem we faced: We experimented with a variety of Projectors from the college&amp;rsquo;s computer lab, we found Mitsubishi XD490u fitting best to our 16:9 needs and the setup alignment. However, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford it, so had to get it issued from the Computer Science engineering Dept. of our college. Although college projector couldn&amp;rsquo;t be availed everytime we need to present the table outside the campus, so we got a task at hand: Making the Multitouch table in a manner that any projector could fit up neatly inside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
