<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anirudh Sharma</title>
    <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Anirudh Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://anirudh.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI Kiran: A Gathering of Physical AI</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/ai-kiran-physical-ai-demo-or-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/ai-kiran-physical-ai-demo-or-die/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The morning of AI Kiran, Lesley Ray was still fixing her BrainHome prototype. Cables, sensor arrays, a laptop that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t talk to the controller board. I watched her troubleshoot with the same calm panic I recognized from my own past. In 2013, I was an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inktalks.com/&#34;&gt;INK&lt;/a&gt; Fellow in Kochi. The night before I was supposed to present on the main stage, I was in my hotel room (jetlagged after a flight from Boston) with my carbon pollution ink prototype in pieces, trying to get the filtration layer to hold. That&amp;rsquo;s Physical Systems. There are no clean deploys. It&amp;rsquo;s machines and systems and soldering irons and things that refuse to boot five minutes before you go on. That&amp;rsquo;s what makes it real. I moved to Silicon Valley 3 years ago where 90% of conversations around me are pure software (nothing wrong with it), but I relate more strongly to problems I see and things I can hold. Multimodality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hard hard user interfaces.</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/hard-hard-user-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/hard-hard-user-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Started as someone doing ActionScript in Macromedia Flash I got into Human-Computer-Interaction after watching Jeff&amp;rsquo;s Hann&amp;rsquo;s multi-touch work. That&amp;rsquo;s the power of a really cool demo that inspired the birth of NUIGroup community which spawned 1000s of makers all around the world making their own projector camera multitouch systems. All of it became mainstream once Apple released the iPhone to the world, and also gave birth to my interest in human-centered engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on better making</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/thoughts-on-better-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/thoughts-on-better-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ideas for better engineering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very passionate about applied and analytical material science with a background in leading startup initiatives. I had built a haptic wearable startup with synthesis gait analysis and haptic feedback through wearables, which exposed me to several schools of design and engineering, and on-ground impact. This had brought me to Boston at MIT to explore advanced forms of man-machine-interfaces. I have transcended from just being a techie, someone who enjoys impacting social problems using tech. In recent years, I have shifted from consumer devices into supply chain innovation leading to carbon offsetting, which exposes me to various operational, perceptive and implementation challenges. I come from a farming family first-generation engineer, born around the invention of the internet&amp;ndash;in the early 90s I used to hear how &lt;strong&gt;repairability&lt;/strong&gt; was a desired feature in tools around us, and &lt;strong&gt;local&lt;/strong&gt; was the way to go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project Ambhibia</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/project-ambhibia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/project-ambhibia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Project Amphibia. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: Carbon linings, electronics, deep water, cell‐laden hydrogels, directly printed wearable systems&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Leaving a set of these images here as an inspiration, and diary entry for adaptive and embodied interfaces. Most of this research in Organic User interfaces have been around tattooing on the skin which is still in its infancy, due to physical limitations of electronic components. Using carbon layering under special materials we can possibly fabricate electro-actuated geometries that can have various sensorial and conductive properties. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if phones were made like shuttlecocks!</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/what-if-phones-were-made-like-shuttlecocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/what-if-phones-were-made-like-shuttlecocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now evolution is a slow process, and as humans and smartphone users this evolution to &amp;rsquo;not drop things&amp;rsquo; is going to only happen in a million years. It&amp;rsquo;s easier to redesign bodies/smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I shattered two phones in the last two years, two screens I got replaced were expensive and quite a hit on the pocket. Humans drop things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://img.gadgethacks.com/img/32/72/63590707031895/0/extreme-trick-lets-you-salvage-lcd-from-your-broken-phone-screen.1280x600.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;A shattered smartphone screen &amp;ndash; the most fragile, expensive part&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;A shattered smartphone screen &amp;ndash; the most fragile, expensive part&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>discordant yet musical whistles</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/discordant-yet-musical-whistles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/discordant-yet-musical-whistles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My house in Delhi has a guard that walks around and whistles all night to keep the thieves away. I am still amused by how the entire street comes together and contributes and hires the guard, instead of complaining and waiting for the Govt. to solve their issues, which is slow as heck.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Its like a citizen contributed and distributed parallel police with evolving protocol, when the systems don&amp;rsquo;t work well. Atleast it keeps the societal interaction intact and neighbors talk, which i believe is a good thing&amp;ndash;communities being vocal about their issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>to write poems or to study poetry?</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/to-write-poems-or-to-study-poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/to-write-poems-or-to-study-poetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was almost the same time 3 years ago when I headed to Boston to pursue research at Fluid Interfaces Group at the MIT Media Lab. Time flied, too fast to perceive it went by..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;college-in-the-middle-of-nowhere&#34;&gt;College in the middle of nowhere&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The life before that was that of running around, seeking each resource actively, hanging onto IRC channels, attending FOSS events, to learn and to meet people in the virtual world of infinite internet. My undergrad college was in the middle of nowhere, with a sorry state education system, and marred by favoritism based on caste and regions. The only escape for the bunch of us was the infinite world of internet and some awesome friends we met during the hostel days back in Bikaner/Rajasthan. We had lost hope to the point that we decided to stop giving a damn about my GPA- to the point that we would travel during our semester exams as we saw no point in taking them (even if we did, we knew the result)- at best IT jobs. It was hard to explain to parents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Word of the day- pokayoke</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/word-of-the-day-pokayoke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/word-of-the-day-pokayoke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;pokayoke!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Poka-yoke (ポカヨケ?) [poka yoke] is a Japanese term that means &amp;ldquo;mistake-proofing&amp;rdquo;. A poka-yoke is any mechanism in a lean manufacturing process that helps an equipment operator avoid (yokeru) mistakes (poka). Its purpose is to eliminate product defects by preventing, correcting, or drawing attention to human errors as they occur.The concept was formalised, and the term adopted, by Shigeo Shingo as part of the Toyota Production System.It was originally described as baka-yoke, but as this means &amp;ldquo;fool-proofing&amp;rdquo; (or &amp;ldquo;idiot-proofing&amp;rdquo;) the name was changed to the milder poka-yoke.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dead or alive? dead after all</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/dead-or-alive-dead-after-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/dead-or-alive-dead-after-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the missing airplane shows that whatever futuristic things we might develop, its important to be in the present(+3 seconds to avoid maybe a dangerous cat to attack you).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;we propose technologies that &amp;lsquo;would touch lives&amp;rsquo; 50 years ahead, and forget to live in/for the present. either we&amp;rsquo;re too much altruistic or just too busy in the rat race of inventing a future that we don&amp;rsquo;t know what will be good for. after all these inventions and industries, has the world become a happier place? Not sure. Yes, we definitely have gotten many superhuman powers now, but the fact everyone has those powers keeps us pushing for inventing even more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bumblebee</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/bumblebee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/bumblebee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to the accredited mechanical flying rules&#xA;the bumble-bee can&amp;rsquo;t fly,&#xA;because of its shape and its weight&#xA;compared with its wing surface.&#xA;But the bumble-bee doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about that&#xA;and does fly nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Rolf Schneider&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magic</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Magic is inspiring. For it can light up the eyes of the sad, make the logical person believe in things he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t otherwise. Any piece of art, music, work that inspires others to me seems like magic. For its so simple yet none of us could make it, other than the creator. Like Naqvi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ink harvester progress 1</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/ink-harvester-progress-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/ink-harvester-progress-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the version 0.1 of the ink-harvester box design. I ended up designing my own enclosure, instead of using Altoids box, though they&amp;rsquo;re the same size.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The suction exhaust pulls the air containing soot particles from the surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A syringe with 1 way valve is being used as the &lt;strong&gt;pump&lt;/strong&gt; which will push the ink into the cartridge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next phase,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Design the carbon separator using capacitive plates. The air comes in with a lot of dust most of which dust and other particles. The powdery black soot separated from rest is what we&amp;rsquo;re interested in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This principle is used in Chimneys to reduce the carbon particles injected into the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About smudges, ink, Altoids box and love.</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/about-smudges-ink-altoids-box-and-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/about-smudges-ink-altoids-box-and-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is not an attempt to win over the pollution. Just a minor itch that led me to build something cool from observations arising from Nostalgia of the days back in India :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia 0 - Just after you&amp;rsquo;re born. ( Suggested by Kunal)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re born in India chances are that your grandma will take some steps to protect you from wicked spirits by smudging kajal onto your eyes. The technique to make kajal is old. Its carbon deposited from burning a low fidelity oil.(mustard etc.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Reality. Really?</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/augmented-reality-really/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/augmented-reality-really/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;Our goal here is to complement rather than replace.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently I came across an article on augmented reality. The term these days is used like a fad. Like in 1970s cell-phone was the hot term, those what it represents today is more than just a cellular phone, its a hell lot of technology in packed in a soapbar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;20 years from now, there would be no difference in real and virtual. We could live what we hallucinate today.  Those who fantasize climbing Himalayas, or walking through streets of Varanasi would just be able to &amp;lsquo;buy&amp;rsquo; the experience, and feel it on their cornea embedded Augmented Reality/AR system. So the meaning of hallucination will evolve as well, which I think I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine right now (book &amp;lsquo;hallucinations of the next decade&amp;rsquo;?).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ideas</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Multiple ideas I was thinking about that could be used to improve people&amp;rsquo;s lives- make new experiences happen, and tap into the unknown&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Sound Glasses.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The user wears the glass and looks at a painting. A large painting. And the system gives audio feedback on the parts highlighted based on an audio command &amp;lsquo;Tell me more&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Technology: Pre-calibrated system.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Easy&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or multiple paintings and it starts speaking about what you&amp;rsquo;re looking at.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel plan tip: Unplanned ones are better</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/travel-plan-tip-unplanned-ones-are-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/travel-plan-tip-unplanned-ones-are-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had forgotten what darkness looks like, what is it to walk under the quiet of the moon by the roar of the waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boston has been beautiful so far, so were the cities I lived in back in India. But the problem with cities is that they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;cities&lt;/em&gt;-loud, fast, and always well lit- even when you don&amp;rsquo;t want! I remember being a child looking at the nightsky and looking at stars more than I could count. This trip made me nostalgic. The sheer pleasure of looking at white blobs as they patterned stories in my empty head ;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silence of the night</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/silence-of-the-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/silence-of-the-night/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The silence of the night and emptiness within reminds me to complete 14 to-do past blogposts that I wrote in my diary ;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looks like am gonna find some OCR goodness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Soon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding images</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/adding-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/adding-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three images varying in direction and intensity of light&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhT3n5pKqCd1eEMHJNjko0XntJUDTjcFnJg6-XzWShjyjgzVXnQdA9Mgsuho8XyXuSTwoxKg1cxxoxoysNcQGYOiM0VxtPlrExhaV3THHDWXEzYPi-YMN9KAsZ_wQseeX6PRi74xkiLXqCp/s1600/IMG_6753.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Soft natural light from one direction&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Soft natural light from one direction&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEisq7-LId0xapmqdLPxgx59d-eC_Zhrowy-2lwM6pTe_4MjQWNvLAc6njmZH4jdiyv-KcMtjJ4MC4YnxeNQVv7hLmgYo9gvcGetIjgubw9U1OidZjTbl5C-SHaaqUEpNqU66dr8potJy4iE/s1600/IMG_6755.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Shifted angle, stronger directional light&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Shifted angle, stronger directional light&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjmgO2QvJbOA9DDNZ-rt0ajvmOmb-COPW9WFGPA_aRUnHC1RwnGkNic5JdMvT3mNaNGej2nQ4SsLS7LT7-Hbor06Uz7i1B_mMwbh7HZEyVwKh-7ZOME4s7riBGNQrC8bXzPlWygneH8Y22H/s1600/IMG_6754.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;High-intensity light creating dramatic contrast&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;High-intensity light creating dramatic contrast&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simple submission of three&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhQbTieD7hmbd0rZ3s7kV1GjZiX_1tojO6BnhVbUoCO3wyhDzXr5BTA2mu-WNSDCW6VGR2f-yqqPBlcNal7l1PJicsAylU5up_zn99D5QKOvCZpbP6hqkpewNoA3WzJoLgel1RcqIIfkP00/s1600/rg.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Three exposures combined for the HDR composite&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Three exposures combined for the HDR composite&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HDR using LocalContrast method. Scroll &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dpreview.com/learn/?/Guides/The_art_of_HDR_Photography_part_1_01.htm&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; down to read more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgWW0k1iSYnKiu1iPKn5Zrv_Hu5KSQjpJfqm1sjurMkGGoDTqSH3mpmPApjVSiYPyrlnTUBRQlwVoga9N9CUa7BBYOCbfSJuxMETpmj-yDAN9tvTPQ8De0e9AUhxwdSh29dT9B-Ovzty0hv/s1600/RGB.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;HDR result using the LocalContrast tonemapping method&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;HDR result using the LocalContrast tonemapping method&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installation inspired by nature.</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/installation-inspired-by-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/installation-inspired-by-nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A beautiful idea! in form of an installation. Gives me goosebumps! :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;video-container&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/41009719&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The way the mechanical parts mimic organic motion &amp;ndash; you can&amp;rsquo;t tell where the engineering ends and nature begins. That&amp;rsquo;s the kind of work that makes me want to run back to the lab and start building something. When machines move like living things, it changes how you feel about them, and that shift in perception is what I think good HCI is really about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NZM-SEC Superfast express that took my &#39;35 hours&#39;</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/nzm-sec-superfast-express-that-took-my-35-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/nzm-sec-superfast-express-that-took-my-35-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I usually cover my long distance travels by air- for it saves time, and is less tiring (and was affordable in the past).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beginning&#34;&gt;The beginning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Call it naivety or my callous attitude, but I completely forgot the fact that its hard to fetch a cheap ticket when your travel plans are made just a day in advance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Owing to recent price inflations and my last minute plans I decided to cover my return journey from Delhi to Hyderabad via train. The decision was taken a day before I wanted to return, i.e. 19th May, high time when there are summer holidays in India. The night before I stood in the train line, with my father and brother, to fetch tatkal tickets. The process is hard- the HTTP fetch request by IRCTC works like a lucky draw). Hence, my attempt ended up futile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>virtually social and socially null :)</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/virtually-social-and-socially-null/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/virtually-social-and-socially-null/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I am writing a personal experience that&amp;rsquo;s not design/tech/tinker related on my blog. So bear with it :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I live alone in Hyderabad now unlike Bikaner and Bangalore where I had close to 10-15 friends around, anytime!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently become a social media aficionado both, on Twitter and Facebook. A behavior change that I saw happened in me when I quit my fulltime job at HP Labs and started dedicating fulltime on lechal(period after March 2012). The lowest spikes are the time when I was busy with &lt;a href=&#34;http://anirudh.me/2011/05/mozart-multimodal-3d-modeling-ui-for-beginners/&#34;&gt;Mozart&lt;/a&gt; project. I am busy now as well, probably starting-up makes you more expressive? Not sure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Le Chal: Haptic shoe for the visually impaired ;)</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/le-chal-haptic-shoe-for-the-visually-impaired/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/le-chal-haptic-shoe-for-the-visually-impaired/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Latest updates on development of Le-Chal shoe can be accessed &lt;a href=&#34;http://anirudh.me/2011/06/le-chal-a-haptic-feedback-based-shoe-for-the-blind/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Touchable and holdable: Beauty of objects</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/touchable-and-holdable-beauty-of-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/touchable-and-holdable-beauty-of-objects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is an auto-rickshaw repair process I regularly notice during my visit to Kanakpura, Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-repair&#34;&gt;The repair&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An image of the interaction while the repair process is on:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiqzXxjScgAee2JaDTHVjmC2uxHVHDqbJcJRh2h5xBpi9r-0DYblfkk6bwS-31FTQG25JrYxRe7_1zPTkLamzJBXM954eik1J8RDZUiH2BI_Yx9spuJfjHP-dfvZazvZEGhkvaYL2tNYzdN/s1600/a1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mechanic&amp;rsquo;s hands-on interaction during auto-rickshaw engine repair&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mechanic&amp;rsquo;s hands-on interaction during auto-rickshaw engine repair&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An image of the parts that are laid down during assembly and disassembly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhT6Uz3vdoo8F7IhM7mc8P1Yox4ste46VrIhK9mxCIXXPdFrtX5wfjQ77YEoep6dEAuAiFjGaFkNA3HIK05-2qwZ2g4YSJfMGpfDfuimeLfqDr3MBHT8k6ZvqU1WpBOKE6uYfX1Iu0SOjIC/s1600/a2.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Disassembled engine parts laid out during the repair&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Disassembled engine parts laid out during the repair&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysing an autorickshaw ride in Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/analysing-an-autorickshaw-ride-in-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/analysing-an-autorickshaw-ride-in-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The bumpy ride on the Bangalore streets triggered a thought the other day, why not log the data and analyse it later(whackily purposeless initially).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The desire to log is esp. a fallout of my recent stint with user studies dealing with data cleaning/analysis and deriving statistical results from it: formally two-way ANOVA tests, T-tests etc. and who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love clean graphs telling a story :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Bangalore autorickshaw, the test vehicle for this experiment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scratch Mini Bootcamp</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/scratch-mini-bootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/scratch-mini-bootcamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So the scratch bootcamp turned out to be fun during my 14 day break from regular research. We traveled 3 cities, 4 schools, and introduced Scratch Programming environment to 8-12 year old kids. Most kids were first time introduced to programming. The novel drag and drop based looping and the fact that other kids from around the world could re-mix, check out their projects,  excited them into coming up with their own ideas, and build them into something usable. The projects involved animations, adding interactivity, and using sprites. Tapan Sharma(student of class 3rd) volunteered and &lt;a href=&#34;http://scratch.mit.edu/users/tappu&#34;&gt;shared some of the projects online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The G1 and the interface blues</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-g1-and-the-interface-blues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-g1-and-the-interface-blues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New year!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;HTC Dev Phone1, first time Android experience!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The device felt loose, just like it would fall apart if I shake it. Why would I? Of-course the accelerometer exists, but then 500 $ should make it tough?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although its late, in Jan 2011, I got an Android phone hands-on to try out for some prototyping. Being a iPhone user since the first gen, i found many contrasts, mostly being on the design and interface side. I had my brief stint of Android with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iddhis.com/&#34;&gt;Shreekant &lt;/a&gt;on his Galaxy, the interaction felt wonderful and intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plans for the Mozilla Firefox Multitouch UX</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/plans-for-the-mozilla-firefox-multitouch-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/plans-for-the-mozilla-firefox-multitouch-ux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am quite interested in exploring the Multitouch scenario on Mozilla Firefox for my project under &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.felipe.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Felipe&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gerv.net/&#34;&gt;Gerv&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; mentorship. Working with Mozilla Team design team members (&lt;a href=&#34;http://limi.net/&#34;&gt; Alexander Limi&lt;/a&gt;) and mentors is turning out to be a great experience so far. I am learning a lot of new things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Browsing the web is a very distributed activity with a lot of interactions possible. My aim would be to design a minimalist interface, that is slick, fast, and non-obtrusive. Hence devoted past couple of weeks researching on the topic and doing some user study with Natural User Interface Group members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Last few days at college</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/last-few-days-at-college/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/last-few-days-at-college/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just taking a moment out to dedicate some space from one of the last few days that remain at college. The experience turned out very good, and will always remain with me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sad and happy. The nights were busy coding, the days were spent tinkering and building things with whatever we could find. Bikaner gave me everything &amp;ndash; the jugaad, the friendships, the confidence to just try stuff. Onward now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CV dilemma</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/cv-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/cv-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looks like there&amp;rsquo;s a problem with OpenCV&amp;rsquo;s distributed parameterization of coordinates used during the camera calibration tasks.  Three distinct sources of information on img distortion formulae apparently give three non-equivalent description of the parameters and equations involved:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1)&lt;/strong&gt; In their book &amp;ldquo;Learning OpenCV&amp;rdquo;  write regarding lens distortion:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$x_{\text{corrected}} = x(1 + k_1 r^2 + k_2 r^4 + k_3 r^6) + [2p_1 xy + p_2(r^2 + 2x^2)]$$&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;$$y_{\text{corrected}} = y(1 + k_1 r^2 + k_2 r^4 + k_3 r^6) + [p_1(r^2 + 2y^2) + 2p_2 xy]$$&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Multitouch Notebook, Mozilla Labs, GSoC and fun</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/new-multitouch-notebook-mozilla-labs-gsoc-and-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/new-multitouch-notebook-mozilla-labs-gsoc-and-fun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its week two weeks since I finally bought myself a &lt;strong&gt;Acer Aspire 5738 pzg&lt;/strong&gt; multitouch (actually dual-touch) notebook.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Acer Aspire 5738PZG dual-touch notebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Its a welcome change, since for the past two years our multitouch experiments required a lot of background effort due to our utter dependence on our custom built MT screen. The capacitive screen is good, its responsive and precise. They&amp;rsquo;ve a Python apploader called Acer Touch Portal which runs a couple of cool Microsoft Surface apps (Globe, Collage, Blackboard etc.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>i wish i had other options</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/i-wish-i-had-other-options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/i-wish-i-had-other-options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a lot of misery I thought no device is worth respect more than a device. Lol! not true. The reason was my bad home button. right, its the only button on the device.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I happened to take a sharp swivel knife and pop my iPhone&amp;rsquo;s case open.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhHC1jEa6zVTVgcoLPjSBlobn_qgLd9IUX2Pq9eX3h2on9VG5rvvbXv8EBnU2sWQz9w9Yj1-Tk-3ow4P3PoP3yVdX_AXOgikJi5yclZUTZ085nIPkwm2_3-2oiKTLiYse4G5TID3_qmWlg7/s1600/IMG_3011.GIF&#34; alt=&#34;iPhone opened up, showing the corroded grounding strap on the home button&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;iPhone opened up, showing the corroded grounding strap on the home button&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>with all the summer love- The Indian iPad!</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/with-all-the-summer-love-the-indian-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/with-all-the-summer-love-the-indian-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am waiting to see what happens to the indigenous Notion Ink Adam and Apple iPad. Will it even turn out to be a war? Both are not released yet- but the coming summer isn&amp;rsquo;t far away too. Should i quote &amp;ldquo;breathless anticipation usually reserved by nubile nymphets for rakish rockers.&amp;rdquo; :-P&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Notion Ink Adam tablet with its Pixel Qi display&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adam beats iPad hands down in all hardware specs. The hardware, the software ( Yay! Android and Ubuntu combo is superawesome) but yes we know of the Apple&amp;rsquo;s marketing strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iPhone Photograph Recovery experience</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-iphone-photograph-recovery-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-iphone-photograph-recovery-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Around a week back while playing around with a friend, i took some photographs from my iPhone that were one of the most inseparable ones to me. Due to a stupid backup method, I happened to accidently delete and lose them in a jiffy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The odds to recovering them were low, and i took some precautions like minimally using my iPhone so that disk Read+Write sessions do not overwrite the data permanently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternative hack for the Gesture Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/alternative-hack-for-the-gesture-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/alternative-hack-for-the-gesture-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Long time for this post too! eh. mugging for the exams is quite a shakle to breakaway from :-P The reason I am writing this post amid the tests is being overwhelmed by Rahul Motiyar&amp;rsquo;s new multitouch monitor mount hack. The thoughts from the B&amp;rsquo;lore trip and the above work culminated :-P&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I happened to visit and take a look around HPL India B&amp;rsquo;lore. The way gesture keyboard solves the problem of indic languges was sure eye catcher. Its a tablet with a Stylus input interface using which a computer newbie can type in Hindi almost with zero learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pwned! FOSS event concluded!</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/pwned-foss-event-concluded/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/pwned-foss-event-concluded/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Duh! Long overdue for this post. Almost 500 students attended the FOSS Fest during &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sakshama.org/&#34;&gt;Sakshama&lt;/a&gt; :-) Mostly undergrad prefinal and final year engineering students. We started barely 20 days before and managed to finish everything right in time! quickfire way :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of us wishfully had almost none or less than 2-3 hours of sleep for the 3 days of the event, it was fun!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reason: The days were reserved for the FOSS talks, and the mid-nights for Hands-on DIY sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FOSS GN09 Coming Up Soon</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/foss-gn09-coming-up-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/foss-gn09-coming-up-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve planned a FOSS event in college from 28-31st October. We&amp;rsquo;ll be talking to people about enhancing their contribution to the commnity, code, and the spirit behind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Probably we&amp;rsquo;ll be having &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.niyam.com/&#34;&gt;Niyam Bhushan&lt;/a&gt;. So we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking and doing an unconference on Human Computer Interaction, Multitouch, programming gestures, why a programmer should consider design while writing code etc. We&amp;rsquo;ve also planned to do a hackfest on how to build a DIY multitouch table with junk hardware etc. and writing some gestures code in AS3&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intuitive Gesture Pad for Hindi typing</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/intuitive-gesture-pad-for-hindi-typing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/intuitive-gesture-pad-for-hindi-typing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I happened to stumble across a gesture pad devised by Shekhar Borgaonkar. Needless to say, its one of the most wonderful innovations as per inputting Devnagri(Hindi) script is concerned. Due to its complexity, the Hindi based keyboards used today aren&amp;rsquo;t user friendly at all. A beginner cannot think of using the same for text entry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Interfacing the same to a touchscreen/stylus-input make it intuitive, and hence cut down the learning curve required to type hindi into Computers/cellphones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Received the GSoC certificate</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/received-the-gsoc-certificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/received-the-gsoc-certificate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally I got my GSoC certificate of completion. Huge thanks to my mentor Pawel Solyga(solydzajs) and Google Open Source Programs Office.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Fedex shipping had twisted and crumpled and torn it a bit on the way from Googleplex to Delhi, a little trick called &amp;ldquo;lamination&amp;rdquo; helped it look as good as a new one ( atleast in the scanned image below). yay!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg2sqXs68zWW7YuUk9iYWxdLvxTV3KT8smwzf4xg8S-8LkWOM1QMde4VM7D4xBIgqdVg0dH7LOAiK-2OvoVtZJ-CXUaJUplVyUexUzjDIH3jMA8Fm2A-rnZYJqwJBtsuzBbHxrJJIa-avGW/s1600/gsoc09&amp;#43;certificate.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Google Summer of Code 2009 certificate of completion&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Google Summer of Code 2009 certificate of completion&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alpha Tests</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/alpha-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/alpha-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the help of Soy Productions i could get a small demo video. Due to table configuration problems a good recording couldn&amp;rsquo;t be done for now at my end. Soon our multitouch wall will be up and running.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, This is how camera manipulation would look as of now. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if we come up with new ideas soon.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Task TBD - Make touch sensitive drawing and camera manipulation modes switch to each other. Waiting for friend - Pecan to arrive soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approaching Final evals</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/approaching-final-evals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/approaching-final-evals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;pencils down&amp;rdquo; date for GSoC is approaching fast. This is the core of the work during this time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. Code cleaning. Decided to keep the previous ruby tuio client experiments&amp;rsquo; work safe in the repository (pre-midterms GSoC work). It might be useful in the future development where better and refined gestures might be inculcated.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. Code commenting wherever necessary&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;. Documentation&amp;rsquo;s skeleton done&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3.a) Compile HowTo&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;3.b) Readme&amp;rsquo;s&#xA;3.c) Changelog&#xA;3.d) Etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Mode</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/drawing-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/drawing-mode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just figured out that drawing using gestures in a limited ability environment like SketchUp, is only possible in theory. Practicalizing it would be a waste of effort.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If i go following the advice of NUI veterans Infrared Pen/Stylus should be the best way to draw in SketchUp. Design Wise it should look like this :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing is &amp;ndash; fingers are great for grabbing, rotating, zooming. Big broad gestures. But drawing a precise line in 3D? Your finger blob is like 20 pixels wide, you can&amp;rsquo;t see what&amp;rsquo;s under it, and you have zero precision. I tried it on our table and it was just frustrating. A stylus gives you a fine tip and you can actually see where you&amp;rsquo;re drawing. Duh! Sometimes you discover the obvious only after banging your head for a week :P&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Gestures test</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/first-gestures-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/first-gestures-test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s how our first gestures tests came out as using TUIO simulator. The BSR watermark is from the ahh! propietary screen recorder software. Why isn&amp;rsquo;t it Open Source!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The good news &amp;ndash; basic rotate and zoom gestures are working with the TUIO simulator input. The not-so-good news &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s noticeable lag between the gesture and SketchUp responding, the XML file read approach has its limits. But hey, the model actually moves when you pinch and twist on screen, that first moment was a mini yay! moment :-) Now to make it buttery smooth..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ConceptS: Our new Multitouch Wall</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/concepts-our-new-multitouch-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/concepts-our-new-multitouch-wall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite a long time since we didn&amp;rsquo;t show our work done in pre-summer-holidays time at IIT delhi&amp;rsquo;s Design lab. Here&amp;rsquo;s a sneak peek into the multitouch wall done by Sparsh team during their IIT Delhi stay.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hail NUI :) The upcoming video will show some custom applications with object marking.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Building the wall at IIT Delhi&amp;rsquo;s design lab was proper jugaad &amp;ndash; we sourced a projector, an acrylic sheet, IR LEDs, and a PS3 Eye camera, put it all together in a couple of days. The best part was showing it to people who&amp;rsquo;d never seen multitouch before, their faces when objects on screen responded to their fingers was priceless. Sparsh team putting it together with almost zero budget, that&amp;rsquo;s how we roll :P&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Usability Survey Results &#34;How will Multitouch on Google Sketchup feel like&#34;</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/usability-survey-results-how-will-multitouch-on-google-sketchup-feel-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/usability-survey-results-how-will-multitouch-on-google-sketchup-feel-like/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well here the survey results we conducted on the NUIGroup community :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You will require to zoom in several times, as its a clumsy fit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribd.com/doc/17871504/Multi-Touch-SketchUp-Survey-Google-Summer-of-Code-2009&#34;&gt;Multi Touch SketchUp Survey Results- Google Summer of Code 2009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Pecan, Colin and Rishi :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gestures Plan</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/gestures-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/gestures-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My thoughts were triggered after I read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.billbuxton.com/multitouchOverview.html&#34;&gt;Bill Buxton argument&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We must focus on &lt;em&gt;streamlining&lt;/em&gt; the interaction. by number of gestures &lt;strong&gt;minimum&lt;/strong&gt;, using them only when they&amp;rsquo;re required and &lt;strong&gt;naturally usable&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; Simpler and better SketchUp design and modeling experience. This implies that we should using Multitouch in only one thing -&amp;gt; Camera motions in Sketchup i.e. Zoom, PAN and Orbit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two modes I am thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MODE 1 Camera = Initialized using a Button1 from a new SketchUp MT Toolbar&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am trying to.</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/i-am-trying-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/i-am-trying-to/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;make a toolbar and User Interface for the plugin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Figure out how the overlay circular menu will work on SketchUp-&amp;gt; This could pop open after someone makes a NUI swish(~) gesture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The circular menu part is what&amp;rsquo;s keeping me up at night. On a multitouch surface you don&amp;rsquo;t have a right-click, so you need some gesture to trigger the menu &amp;ndash; and it has to feel natural, not forced. Trying a few things out, will post screenshots when something clicks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new inspiration</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/a-new-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/a-new-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just happened to see this video off &lt;a href=&#34;http://theclevermonkey.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Richard Monsol Haefel&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; blog. The way this concept model has been done is awesome, atleast it shows what the future has in store for CAD modelers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see someone in the CAD world doing something innovative. Must admit that the guys doing the modeling are creative and all set to change the scenario :-) I&amp;rsquo;ve some ideas running up my head now, and I feel re-fuelled with energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates Post midterm new</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/updates-post-midterm-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/updates-post-midterm-new/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, the EventRelay was so wonderful we just knew :-)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On 24th and 25th July I was busy with my Google Summer of Code doing:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Wiki Page with information about the project readily accessible&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some Code Cleanup&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adding protected bins on the the repository, so that mentors could try out each.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Change-log maintainance&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart this I am working atm on how gestures will work now. A separate blogpost should explain how our team is going to go about it. :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post Midterms Update</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/post-midterms-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/post-midterms-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve now been able to trick SketchUp now to pose TUIO data is SketchUp data by posting the TUIO data as a SketchUp &amp;ldquo;User&amp;rdquo; message type. It would then be in sync with SketchUp events rather than asynchronous TUIO events.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This way we can sub-class SketchUp (like EventRelay), pass the data off to the SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s embed Ruby as a &lt;strong&gt;Synchronous&lt;/strong&gt; event. Here&amp;rsquo;s the result of DLL &amp;ldquo;puts&amp;rdquo;-ing cursors successfully to the SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s embed Ruby Console via a Ruby API puts statement:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pre Mids Update</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/pre-mids-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/pre-mids-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. Added a new blogpost (last), regarding my gesture implementation thought.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;. The repo had gone erroneous due to cleanup and I faced some issues while using the Merge command. Things are fine now &amp;ndash; fixed by Pawel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The indented commit message was: &amp;ldquo;Remove non-required components that came while freezing required filesets. Code commenting and cleaning updations. Adding a Readme for Current Status and project details.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the research and work I did yesterday, got an exam in an hour. GSoC + semester exams running in parallel is not for the faint-hearted hehe. Off to cram some OS concepts now, kthxbai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Future work</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/future-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/future-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Post midterm tasks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We were working on &lt;code&gt;mouse_event&lt;/code&gt; Function (&lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms646260%28VS.85%29.aspx&#34;&gt;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms646260(VS.85).aspx&lt;/a&gt;) for the possible events that MultitouchSU DLL can inject into the SketchUp windows simply by specifying &lt;code&gt;{LBUTTON UP|DOWN} {MBUTTON UP|DOWN}{RBUTTON UP|DOWN}{MOUSEMOVE x,y}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This indeed is pretty raw, but I thought good enough for the first version. We could have got more sophisticated later with something like &lt;code&gt;Click(Left|Middle|Right count)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;MouseMove( 0|Left|Middle|Right, x, y, rate)&lt;/code&gt; etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an example how it&amp;rsquo;ll be done, (&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/eventrelay/source/browse/trunk/devel/MSWrunmacro.cpp?r=113&#34;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/eventrelay/source/browse/trunk/devel/MSWrunmacro.cpp?r=113&lt;/a&gt;) at Function &lt;code&gt;void MSW_ProcessMacro::InjectNamedMouseMacro(string&amp;amp; namedMacroStr)&lt;/code&gt;. A &lt;code&gt;MOVEMOUSETO(x,y)&lt;/code&gt; function will have to be added.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updates</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgo5mnsgwU962lnhjP1hz-1tnoG1hhPYIvnNdVDz4AvSPiEMQ-o6trtf9W0Fq7zo7WoS5DPQazktHVqy5GzlFiUd60Wrk4tiZSNaYvQ8hbDF0MgbEc_SYRyTxJzChFaTRRDgS2rnh0xva6I/s1600/s&amp;#43;cr.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;TUIO messages received in SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s debug console via EventRelay&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;TUIO messages received in SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s debug console via EventRelay&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The TUIO messages are being received by the Debug window within Sketchup when we run the TUIO simulator, see screenshot&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Gestures still to be implemented. Still trying to find out what&amp;rsquo;s going to be the best strategy for the same. Whether to emulate the mouse, or to go with macros.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Pecan and his plugin EventRelay, which really proved to be the way to implement the DLL within.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s begin with what all I...</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/lets-begin-with-what-all-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/lets-begin-with-what-all-i/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s begin with what all I tried at my end that &lt;strong&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t work&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Direct Implementation of Ruby Client within Sketchup&lt;/em&gt; - Didn&amp;rsquo;t work due to the Ruby API&amp;rsquo;s limitation under SketchUp.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;pyGE_touch&lt;/em&gt; - Tried to hack around Win32COM interface to make SketchUp respond to pyGE like script. Didn&amp;rsquo;t workout just because we don&amp;rsquo;t have a COM interface in SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s API.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Using the SKSocket class&lt;/em&gt; - Though it showed some initial success the if the SKSocket was buffering and finally flushed the data all at once, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best of experiences. As per the blogpost on &lt;a href=&#34;http://touchaddict.blogspot.com/2009/06/some-changes-to-strategy.html&#34;&gt;http://touchaddict.blogspot.com/2009/06/some-changes-to-strategy.html&lt;/a&gt; its explianed how it worked for a while &amp;ndash; gave me a lot of hope, but eventually failed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some changes to the strategy</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/some-changes-to-the-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/some-changes-to-the-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally I am dumping the SkSockets approach with our plugin. Though it showed some initial success the if the SKSocket was buffering and finally flushed the data all at once. Which won&amp;rsquo;t work for this as we need constant refresh of data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 - started osc.exe - set it for small screen size and low framerate.&#xA;2 - used toxy_win UDP to TCP proxy server (gave a link)&#xA;3 - Start the tuioconn.rb code in SU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updations</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/updations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/updations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Got back from home after 5 days, it was probably a long gap, resumed the GSoC work now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The TUIO client now appends cursor coordinates to a text file, the x_pos and y_pos, example coordinates 0.535937488079071, 0.410416662693024.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Writing a ruby script SketchUp plugin that reads the TUIO cursor information from the text file.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The downsides to this after discussing with Jay Morrisson:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s subject to slowdown by writing to/reading from disk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The serialization has to be done by oneself&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After this works I&amp;rsquo;ll consider one more option of trying the dRB ruby gems (Distributed Queue in Ruby) since we can just focus on the sketchup integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/dilemma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would be the best between:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;pyGE Touch like implementation under SketchUp, doable if SketchUp can support WIN32COM interfacing &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/pymt/source/browse/examples/kaswy/PyGE_touch.py&#34;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/pymt/source/browse/examples/kaswy/PyGE_touch.py&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Going with Aberrant&amp;rsquo;s TUIO Client within SketchUp, we won&amp;rsquo;t continue with it since thread calculation within SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s scripting is quite a pain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Write TUIO to Text/XML, and get it read by SketchUp. That&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re busy doing now. After this works, we&amp;rsquo;ll work with code refinement and optimizing the stuff before moving to gestures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously I had a word with patali, regarding pyGE if something similar will work with Google SketchUp. We can go with an external script, that will sends TUIO using &lt;code&gt;win32com&lt;/code&gt; directly &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/pymt/source/browse/examples/kaswy/PyGE_touch.py&#34;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/pymt/source/browse/examples/kaswy/PyGE_touch.py&lt;/a&gt; like passing commands. That&amp;rsquo;s how the Google Earth is controlled via python and we can make these commands user defined:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We run an external script and this script launches the Google SketchUp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Takes in the TUIO, processes gestures and talks to SketchUp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But we will resort to this option if all else fails, after trying this successfully I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to usual TUIO implementation within SketchUp. Started to try if that works out with Sketchup. The only difference being that Google Earth comes with a direct WIN32 COM interface and SketchUp doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But we might be able to add that support via a DLL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Report 1</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/report-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/report-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past 4 days I was working with my GSoC project and so far I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to do the following except my to successfully let Google SketchUp talk to TUIO.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup the iconset, the UI - that&amp;rsquo;d enable the enabling and disabling of the extension from SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s toolbar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Two operation modes for the plugin SketchUp, B1-Control Navigation B2-Enable Drawing/Sketching&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trying with TUIO data into SketchUp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The TUIO part is the tricky bit &amp;ndash; just wish that the Google SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s API was a little more developer friendly.. but that&amp;rsquo;s what makes it fun to hack around. Slowly getting somewhere :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precoding updates</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/precoding-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/precoding-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Code Repository setup at &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/sketchupmultitouch/&#34;&gt;Google Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEihu0eOvmHbVGGH0G1W3N4jN4oBq-R2oNunCIHk1Zhi6yZJSURXLS4qY00bjsGe1z4OCHpAAgElE9nhAZ3Tjv2g5pXf_GwokbLwKiutqSPuzSjlUecFq6y8HJVBYW-nbEU8mNa7GsR8DXcu/s1600/tuio&amp;#43;ruby.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently I tried out Colin Harris&amp;rsquo;s Ruby &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/aberant/tuio-ruby/tree/master&#34;&gt;TUIO client&lt;/a&gt;, it took me a little longer time (more than expected) to figure out if its working since I was using Adobe Air based SimTouch.air and socketserver executable to do my tests - which didnt work with our Ruby Client. Though later it responded perfectly with ReactiVision TUIO Simulator 1.4 . I could print the TUIO messages :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google SoC: I am in :)</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-i-am-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-i-am-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After falcon4ever and tito&amp;rsquo;s hint I was keeping my fingers crossed. Phew ! at 12:30 AM IST 22 April dot, the results for Google Summer of Code -2009 were announced. Sudhanshu broke me the news on call, I was in ! It was one of the best moments of my life- the feeling within was a mix of several emotions. The mood was upbeat, yet I had in mind the upcoming summer ahead. Being selected is just the beginning, the real groundwork starts now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed an idea for GSoC 2009</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/proposed-an-idea-for-gsoc-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/proposed-an-idea-for-gsoc-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proposed an Idea for Google Summer of Code to port Google SketchUp to Multitouch. Users would be able to do 3D modeling with simple and intuitive gestures. An Extension Module that would allow Google SketchUp to receive TUIO and hence allow manipulations via Multitouch gestures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lack of a CAD software that could be used via Multitouch has been the motivating factor behind this proposal. Eversince I used the Sketches application on iPhone &amp;ndash; which enables 2D drawing using Multitouch, I felt like doing something similar on my FTIR setup. Adding multitouch ability to an easy to use CAD/modeling software - Google SketchUp would not only make the design process intuitive but also add a lot to the usability factor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stood First - this time its BITS Pilani</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/stood-first-this-time-its-bits-pilani/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/stood-first-this-time-its-bits-pilani/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjH420JPGImfnrrR_WtHxM5bnZueYdT0KjO_Xvm5yZaMXhTXAoqOXz3JnY2T-NnX3lnb_Q84RycYzaMaLdVruiLNR-UNbIZkIXmF7u87S_8GwsK4fNjRSq0kKEkE047hU0NaeBe1akTZ9VK/s1600/DSC02452.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Demonstrating the multitouch table at BITS Pilani Apogee 2009&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Demonstrating the multitouch table at BITS Pilani Apogee 2009&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjDaoSu-GfbMEGxu69zE3j4QRE7f1gdNmIjQaf5kPVmcW24qk_FKN-r300USlJjoz-exwaBEbLW6wEJD_ZfzSPqcwkz1uZQj107V3M9wQx18I0_3R4Bk7YBz-HvY8dSxwUwze2NHxOL-Jz4/s1600/DSC02440.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Audience trying the multitouch surface at the showcase&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Audience trying the multitouch surface at the showcase&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhZ-Qhe3YsAgvNr9OF2YGPxKP6O4IIAAmyGveLGRbiTNLcatnRNcFZMa-Py1dZoRaPOFzIfm-IF2dZD8wLBJDTmPQ0lrus-YFQXSM_QazjxXv8SscdbD7g-t_E6Ujl63YXJ3k5JpB1ZrTkx/s1600/DSC02438.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;The multitouch table setup at the Apogee event venue&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;The multitouch table setup at the Apogee event venue&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We showcased how multitouch technology is going to change the way we interact with machines. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nuigroup.com/&#34;&gt;NUIGroup&lt;/a&gt; community, we could showcase some applications done by Seth Sandler and Lawrence Muller at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bits-apogee.org/&#34;&gt;Apogee 2009&lt;/a&gt; - held annually at BITS Pilani. In addition to this how to make a Flash App from scratch - with TUIO data (OSC implemented) sent by Touchlib.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Timeline for GSoC 2010 :-)</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/visual-timeline-for-gsoc-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/visual-timeline-for-gsoc-2010/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi-TUgjJ4uq_GmyXTyVSwrIl9Q_G6O4PEDNaHfmpS5cv-z50_am6mRYYogvjoIAkO_-h-gPLPn8Zz2ZLtmCfWbAhvSc3NUSAORtAHtJd2SlCseM_XQXDKSLXAIzbhZrVLnMauVK8rXIEe73/s1600/gsoc10timeline.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;NUIGroup community timeline for Google Summer of Code 2010&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;NUIGroup community timeline for Google Summer of Code 2010&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is second iteration of the Google Summer of Code 2010 Timeline contributed to Google by the NUIGroup community :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google SoC is on!</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-is-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-is-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;yoo ! Google Summer of Code list was announced yesterday , and its great to see NUIGroup on it. Well i&amp;rsquo;ll be going with my own idea this time. Have been playing around and exploring with the RUBY API and C++ SDK that comes with Google Sketchup. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it goes, I just posted a request for ideas and suggestions on NUIGroup at &lt;a href=&#34;http://nuigroup.com/forums/viewthread/4801/&#34;&gt;http://nuigroup.com/forums/viewthread/4801/&lt;/a&gt; ..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Apps and some bite of Python</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/new-apps-and-some-bite-of-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/new-apps-and-some-bite-of-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well now I am learning actionscript from Scratch and planning to do some Multitouch apps using it. We happen to be fans of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.nuigroup.com/Rotatablescalable&#34;&gt;RotatableScalable Class&lt;/a&gt; by NUIGroup, which has some prewritten magic that we can directly extend in our code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another thing that deserves a mention is &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/pymt/&#34;&gt;pyMT&lt;/a&gt;, which Sharath introduced us to, who happens to be a bigtime fan of the Python language and contributor this project. He&amp;rsquo;s doing his final year project with his team back there in Mangalore , and hey, pyMT&amp;rsquo;s Python apps look great !&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Prize at IIT Kanpur&#39;s Techkriti</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/first-prize-at-iit-kanpurs-techkriti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/first-prize-at-iit-kanpurs-techkriti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We got our table running at Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur&amp;rsquo;s annual technical festival- Techkriti, one of the largest ones in India and voila! got First Prize there :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Number of Teams at the exhibit - 20&#xA;Number of Projects that applied - approx 400&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of hardware including the whole wooden box setup and the large projector had to be shipped around 300 Kilometers from here- and explaining Multitouch/FTIR/NUIGroup to the audience for 3 long days countless number of times. And that paid off well :) with some moolah raking in, well the first prize got us richer by Rs. 30000/- , enough money to let us by the new Lasers and a couple of cameras for a new multitouch setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Got a new site,</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/got-a-new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/got-a-new-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our new website is now hosted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sparsh-i.com/&#34;&gt;www.sparsh-i.com&lt;/a&gt;. The Vimeo Video on the homepage made it popular and hit the digg frontpage :) ! its a great feeling ! The video received more than 30 comments in 24 hours of launching &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/2953423&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/2953423&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sparsh : A touch sensitive desktop</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/sparsh-a-touch-sensitive-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/sparsh-a-touch-sensitive-desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sparsh is a touch sensitive desktop for everyone which allows us to stay in touch with our touches on a simple desktop. It works in same manner we can interact with all our stuff&amp;rsquo;s every day, it just manipulates the digital contents of computer and gives us a virtual look&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There will be a big range of software&amp;rsquo;s which works on principal of Multitouch. Soon a day will come when everyone is flushing out there desktop computer and installing a Multitouch screen&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woodwork Done</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/woodwork-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/woodwork-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg4L1qcN6FVbDpPYfXu4yGVThY-Mj4k7Ho171Ey8TtkvQ-xiQvlFeDC7ndsh05D3xu56pkp0py8hRD6nWw3Xpt7JPkLAhzQ7FZ5ccHvC49m_Mhk5a6eQx-1314tK9sQqQENhbs6Qrs54zc3/s1600/IMG_aaa0670.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Assembled wooden frame for the multitouch table&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Assembled wooden frame for the multitouch table&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the help and suggestions of local carpenters we&amp;rsquo;re now done with the woodwork of our table, a couple of modifications are yet to be done. Although everything now fits in well- the acrylic frame, the projector and the modded camera.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9C1drMGDZKajkFNa4oe4NA9lqWXU3TTAlWfDZGkd0qi1ASMTOkEG_7oP39FhOqRAeA_muGCapbA64BkPFXv0DkOnfepsVkuT7Lg7mI79eivCJePsod7ibTtKXE0GeK0bVqg7TV6JvUTpw/s1600/rahul.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rahul working on the table with acrylic frame and camera fitted&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rahul working on the table with acrylic frame and camera fitted&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And we got our much awaited blobs</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/and-we-got-our-much-awaited-blobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/and-we-got-our-much-awaited-blobs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After modifying the Microsoft Lifecam VX-1000 we were ready for our first test, if we were getting the blobs or not. The first shot went great, we got what we had imagined as seen in the NUI videos. The clean blobs are the heart and soul of every Multi-touch display based on FTIR. The couple of screenshots we took are attached with this post. We were elated!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjnodt0hrvMdTTtQEx3DM9g21fOEj3Uq9lau9Tt2ZvDBGD5XEf2UzpqKgsquCnWb2P6o2BFQMyouHRjdaElDMrV2a_nXnjNqjjwDl_ezwcM3yGog__PUkHGCWKjbefBsjVPUfnnzLvOS1IO/s1600/DSC03016.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;First successful FTIR blob detection from finger touches&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;First successful FTIR blob detection from finger touches&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Done ! the FTIR acrylic frame</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/done-the-ftir-acrylic-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/done-the-ftir-acrylic-frame/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After much haggling and bargaining we got our 6 mm thick plexi-glass sheet, after manual polishing and shining the task at hand was to fit in the LED&amp;rsquo;s inside so as to facilitate the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.nyu.edu/%7Ejhan/ftirtouch/&#34;&gt;FTIR&lt;/a&gt; ( Frustrated Total Internal Reflection), the principle behind the project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEipWoo46HpaaWTY6cmmSWiZDU8OVA78OZbASJg-wJGYA32R-z2doux6wSNzXNOUss8iES2VJrE6BxtMrg0fumenzWc7KDeQO4eOiWxjt6QzL9mMoQo7zcHqlauQfk3MHPYYAbxPcx4zgKtK/s1600/ftirschematic.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Schematic of frustrated total internal reflection in acrylic&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Schematic of frustrated total internal reflection in acrylic&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since Sudhanshu and Rahul were most affluent in Electronics and Architecture, we moved to R.S. Electronics, owned by Rahul&amp;rsquo;s father &amp;ldquo;Mr. &amp;hellip; &amp;quot; so as to get our LED&amp;rsquo;s fixed in the acrylic frame. After putting in 15 hours we could get the IR LEDs fixed into the wooden frame. Here are some images of Infrared glowing acrylic frame from a night-vision camera.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Final CAD drawing</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-final-cad-drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-final-cad-drawing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEirKoLNhBYYtK0LxN5_NgY6_T-mcCQh3SPHug1a67hjfQG-lrq93gVt8xBSvYuAy1jvI8DJsXbzddJ5tZkrZ_31UJ2o9jKBtWeVUKHRv9MOjN_uaVCxwrFBZmcp63PpdtfCc1Jlrz7uN_Z-/s1600/untitleda.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Final CAD rendering of the multitouch table with acrylic surface&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Final CAD rendering of the multitouch table with acrylic surface&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The CAD Designs for the table</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-cad-designs-for-the-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/the-cad-designs-for-the-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEixnIXXzqxqROHY9v7sLdygjJF_2TP-7gDTGRqO3v2yzYREce55iRfm1BIgHyxHWDe6KSztvVKfCpZdSu3Uk3RKMKydaR7DhMpMBJfDBfM6Gzit4weTD1NY5iDTkSc4uFIcElH2RsH0CJG7/s1600/sparsh.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;CAD design showing adjustable projector rails and shoe-strip mount&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;CAD design showing adjustable projector rails and shoe-strip mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem we faced: We experimented with a variety of Projectors from the college&amp;rsquo;s computer lab, we found Mitsubishi XD490u fitting best to our 16:9 needs and the setup alignment. However, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford it, so had to get it issued from the Computer Science engineering Dept. of our college. Although college projector couldn&amp;rsquo;t be availed everytime we need to present the table outside the campus, so we got a task at hand: Making the Multitouch table in a manner that any projector could fit up neatly inside.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plans for the Multitouch Console :)</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/plans-for-the-multitouch-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/plans-for-the-multitouch-console/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It all started in way back in the humid month of August, 2008, when we planned to build a multitouch table prototype on our own. The terms like &amp;ldquo;complaint surface&amp;rdquo; , &amp;ldquo;display ratio&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;angle of throw&amp;rdquo; started to make a little sense to us. I showed the NUI video to Sudhanshu, Rahul - after getting mesmerized by what all is achievable by Multitouch they got fired up :-) We were a team now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
