<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google Sketchup on Anirudh Sharma</title>
    <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/tags/google-sketchup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google Sketchup on Anirudh Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://anirudh.me/blog/tags/google-sketchup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gestures Plan</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/gestures-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/gestures-plan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My thoughts were triggered after I read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.billbuxton.com/multitouchOverview.html&#34;&gt;Bill Buxton argument&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We must focus on &lt;em&gt;streamlining&lt;/em&gt; the interaction. by number of gestures &lt;strong&gt;minimum&lt;/strong&gt;, using them only when they&amp;rsquo;re required and &lt;strong&gt;naturally usable&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; Simpler and better SketchUp design and modeling experience. This implies that we should using Multitouch in only one thing -&amp;gt; Camera motions in Sketchup i.e. Zoom, PAN and Orbit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are two modes I am thinking about:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MODE 1 Camera = Initialized using a Button1 from a new SketchUp MT Toolbar&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some changes to the strategy</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/some-changes-to-the-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/some-changes-to-the-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally I am dumping the SkSockets approach with our plugin. Though it showed some initial success the if the SKSocket was buffering and finally flushed the data all at once. Which won&amp;rsquo;t work for this as we need constant refresh of data.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 - started osc.exe - set it for small screen size and low framerate.&#xA;2 - used toxy_win UDP to TCP proxy server (gave a link)&#xA;3 - Start the tuioconn.rb code in SU.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously I had a word with patali, regarding pyGE if something similar will work with Google SketchUp. We can go with an external script, that will sends TUIO using &lt;code&gt;win32com&lt;/code&gt; directly &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/pymt/source/browse/examples/kaswy/PyGE_touch.py&#34;&gt;http://code.google.com/p/pymt/source/browse/examples/kaswy/PyGE_touch.py&lt;/a&gt; like passing commands. That&amp;rsquo;s how the Google Earth is controlled via python and we can make these commands user defined:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We run an external script and this script launches the Google SketchUp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Takes in the TUIO, processes gestures and talks to SketchUp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But we will resort to this option if all else fails, after trying this successfully I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to usual TUIO implementation within SketchUp. Started to try if that works out with Sketchup. The only difference being that Google Earth comes with a direct WIN32 COM interface and SketchUp doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But we might be able to add that support via a DLL.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Report 1</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/report-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/report-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past 4 days I was working with my GSoC project and so far I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to do the following except my to successfully let Google SketchUp talk to TUIO.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Setup the iconset, the UI - that&amp;rsquo;d enable the enabling and disabling of the extension from SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s toolbar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Two operation modes for the plugin SketchUp, B1-Control Navigation B2-Enable Drawing/Sketching&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Trying with TUIO data into SketchUp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The TUIO part is the tricky bit &amp;ndash; just wish that the Google SketchUp&amp;rsquo;s API was a little more developer friendly.. but that&amp;rsquo;s what makes it fun to hack around. Slowly getting somewhere :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precoding updates</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/precoding-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/precoding-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Code Repository setup at &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/p/sketchupmultitouch/&#34;&gt;Google Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;entry-figure&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEihu0eOvmHbVGGH0G1W3N4jN4oBq-R2oNunCIHk1Zhi6yZJSURXLS4qY00bjsGe1z4OCHpAAgElE9nhAZ3Tjv2g5pXf_GwokbLwKiutqSPuzSjlUecFq6y8HJVBYW-nbEU8mNa7GsR8DXcu/s1600/tuio&amp;#43;ruby.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently I tried out Colin Harris&amp;rsquo;s Ruby &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/aberant/tuio-ruby/tree/master&#34;&gt;TUIO client&lt;/a&gt;, it took me a little longer time (more than expected) to figure out if its working since I was using Adobe Air based SimTouch.air and socketserver executable to do my tests - which didnt work with our Ruby Client. Though later it responded perfectly with ReactiVision TUIO Simulator 1.4 . I could print the TUIO messages :-)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google SoC: I am in :)</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-i-am-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-i-am-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After falcon4ever and tito&amp;rsquo;s hint I was keeping my fingers crossed. Phew ! at 12:30 AM IST 22 April dot, the results for Google Summer of Code -2009 were announced. Sudhanshu broke me the news on call, I was in ! It was one of the best moments of my life- the feeling within was a mix of several emotions. The mood was upbeat, yet I had in mind the upcoming summer ahead. Being selected is just the beginning, the real groundwork starts now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Proposed an idea for GSoC 2009</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/proposed-an-idea-for-gsoc-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/proposed-an-idea-for-gsoc-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Proposed an Idea for Google Summer of Code to port Google SketchUp to Multitouch. Users would be able to do 3D modeling with simple and intuitive gestures. An Extension Module that would allow Google SketchUp to receive TUIO and hence allow manipulations via Multitouch gestures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lack of a CAD software that could be used via Multitouch has been the motivating factor behind this proposal. Eversince I used the Sketches application on iPhone &amp;ndash; which enables 2D drawing using Multitouch, I felt like doing something similar on my FTIR setup. Adding multitouch ability to an easy to use CAD/modeling software - Google SketchUp would not only make the design process intuitive but also add a lot to the usability factor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google SoC is on!</title>
      <link>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-is-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anirudh.me/blog/google-soc-is-on/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;yoo ! Google Summer of Code list was announced yesterday , and its great to see NUIGroup on it. Well i&amp;rsquo;ll be going with my own idea this time. Have been playing around and exploring with the RUBY API and C++ SDK that comes with Google Sketchup. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it goes, I just posted a request for ideas and suggestions on NUIGroup at &lt;a href=&#34;http://nuigroup.com/forums/viewthread/4801/&#34;&gt;http://nuigroup.com/forums/viewthread/4801/&lt;/a&gt; ..&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
